Planet Express Discount Prisoner Transfer
at your service.
Take a good look, Dr. Brutaloff.
This prison is where you'll be spending
your 300-year sentence.
Yeah, until you're defrosted
and wake up refreshed,
unaware of any time having passed.
He... he heard you!
Oh, please. It's probably just
the carbonite thawing slightly.
Take him down to processing
while I stay here and get hooted at.
Ooh, yeah, baby!
Oh, stop.
Fry, look! That's Silicon Red,
the universe's greatest folk singer!
There's your wallet, your guitar,
and your gun.
You're free to go.
Ah, still cocked.
So, he's a folk singer. So what?
So what? Have you forgotten
my lifelong dream of being a folk singer?
Because I sure have until right now.
Silicon Red! Silicon Red!
Hey, I have a lifelong dream too.
Of not being left alone
with a frozen supervillain.
Don't try anything,
Dr. Brutaloff!
I know karate.
Then I shot him and stabbed him
and stole all his gold
And I tried on his face
while his body turned cold...
Lovely.
Just lovely.
Can I have your autograph,
and also you tell me everything
you know about folk singing,
and I'll take your guitar too?
Old Salmonella?
Son, I ought to kill you for asking.
We met doing hard time
on a Mississippi chain gang.
And she been with me
through 30-odd convictions.
Thirty? You must be
quite a bungling lowlife.
Anyhow, about the guitar.
Aw, come on! I can't be a famous
folk singer without a cool guitar.
Can I at least get a photo?
And before you answer that...
Now I'll just have someone
duplicate your guitar. Thanks, sucker.
You're the sucker, sucker.
See, with all Salmonella and me
been through, her sound is unique.
All your fancy technology
will never be able to copy this guitar.
Using my fancy technology,
I can make an exact copy of this guitar.
Tell me, Dr. Beeler,
will I need to threaten you?
Not at all. You see, nowadays,
we can take a unique and beautiful object,
and easily reduce it
to a formula for mass production.
I call the process "science."
I'll just need to locate that guitar image
on your file system.
Whoa, that's a lot of porn.
Where'd you store the guitar picture?
I don't know. I mainly hang out in here.
Ah-ha, your folk singing folder.
I'll just double-kick on that.
Got it.
Now I'll convert that guitar image
to a wire-frame model.
There, like so.
And send it wirelessly to my 3D printer.
By laying down layer after layer
of nano-plastic,
it can turn your wildest dreams
into ordinary reality.
Witchcraft! Sorcerer!
Neat.
- So, how long will it take?
- Four or five hours.
Shall we adjourn to the porn folder?
I call my new guitar Bender Mae
because Bender may be
the greatest folk singer of all time!
It looks pretty authentic.
You bet it's authentic. See this scratch?
I tell people she got it
while I was doing hard time
with a New Hampshire chain gang.
I have a scratch too.
From where Dr. Brutaloff slashed me
with his finger knives,
right after he thawed out
of his carbonite,
and right before he froze me
in his carbonite
because you deserted me.
Eh, you're always
getting frozen in stuff.
It's your thing, man.
Bender, you're not a folk singer
just 'cause you have a guitar.
And a flannel shirt.
I claim I won it
in a knife fight at J. Crew.
It must be interesting
to win a knife fight.
I wouldn't know.
The point is,
do you even know any actual folk songs?
Actual folk songs
are all public domain.
Where's the money in that?
I'll just make up my own.
But, robot,
you can't just make up folk songs
like you can a medical diploma.
They have to come from the heart.
Wrong again, Zoidberg.
While you were yakking, I downloaded
every folk song in the universe
and analyzed them.
They're only a few basic patterns.
For example...
36% of all folk-song heroes
work on a railroad
and are named "Big" something.
Next slide, please.
75% of these big railroad men
have bad-hearted women
who done them wrong,
usually with a smooth-talking rambler.
There's a lot more, but in the end,
somebody kills somebody, blah, blah, blah.
Somebody kills somebody
Blah, blah, blah
- Catchy.
- Not what I meant,
but don't perform it
without my permission!
Anyway, using this simple formula,
I can generate
as many hit folk songs as I want.
All I need is an audience.
And that's where Silicon Red comes in.
Man, all this corncob pipe smoke
is irritating my stab wounds.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm proud to present,
fresh from another down-home
authentic prison term,
the universe's greatest folk singer,
Silicon Red!
Thank you.
Silicon Red, everyone.
Hey!
I'm Ramblin' Rodriguez,
the new greatest folk singer ever.
And I'm gonna sing my new masterpiece,
The Ballad of Me, Ramblin' Rodriguez.
Well...
My bad-hearted woman
loved a smooth-talking gambler
So I ran him over with my train
Lord, Lord
Yes,I ran him over with my train
That name again is Ramblin' Rodriguez.
Why are they booing me, Silicon?
'Cause your song was insincere, boy.
Now, get out and don't come back
till you've lived a life
worth singing about.
Yes, sir.
And don't go to prison. That's my shtick!
I failed at my lifelong dream again.
How can I be so bad at everything I try
and still be so great?
Bender, you have a lovely baritone,
and you sure can strum
that plastic guitar,
but you can't write a real folk song
about experiences you haven't had.
Yeah, you should write a song
about a heartless robot
who leaves his best friend to be murdered.
Look, Leela, I'd love to write
about my own experiences...
The heartless robot is Bender.
The best friend is me.
How can you people be so blind?
...but I've never picked cotton
or been on top of Old Smokey
or worked on anything
all the livelong day,
let alone a railroad.
Then go live among
the railroad men, why not?
You'll come to understand them,
just as I now understand
the ape-men of Earth.
As stupid as Zoidberg's idea is,
it's brilliant when I have it.
I'm off to the railroad
to become a folk singer.
Uh, I'm looking for
the wrong side of the tracks.
Then you've come
to the right side of the tracks.
Have a seat, stranger.
My name's Bender Rodriguez,
and I want to learn
the railroading business.
Big Caboose. I'm a steel-driving man
working the trans-universal line.
Wow, you've had the exact experiences
I want to steal for my song.
Aw, heck, I'm nothing special.
Just a down-home robot
with a big old hammer.
A hammer, that should be easy to rhyme.
- You done time in the slammer?
- Uh, nope.
- Been to Alabama?
- Sorry.
How's your grammar?
Praiseworthy.
Bender, meet Fast Frank Brogan.
Daredevil engineer
dies in the crash of Old '88.
Dandy Jim and Gus.
Gentlemen hobos with a story to tell.
I was got drunk and ate my big toe.
Can't say I miss it.
And good old Cookie,
the crusty comically inept
geological surveyor.
Jiggers! I dropped my sexton in the stew.
Been up north
Been down south
Got a real weak back
I got a real big mouth
So while Bender goofs off
at some railroad camp,
I have to deliver dynamite
to a railroad camp myself.
And it's the same railroad camp.
I mean, the irony is palpable.
Oops.
Whoopsie.
My bad.
Dibs on the toes.
So how's it going
with the real-world experience?
Have you found a railroad man
to write a song about?
Yep, my good friend Big Something here.
Uh, Caboose.
I'm a steel-driving man,
and there ain't much more to say about me.
Not till now there wasn't.
Well, Big Caboose
wasa steel-drivin' son of a gun
Till a bad-hearted woman he spied...
But, Bender,
I never spied no bad-hearted woman.
In my song you did,
a temptress named, I don't know, Jezebel.
Wow, creativity's hard work.
Ah.
You know my favorite part of your song?
The part where it ended.
Then, settle in,
'cause that's about a half hour from now.
Well, Jezebel's heart did wander
When she saw that ramblin' man
He was tall and dark and shiny
And a native Mexican
That sleazy rambler
sounds an awful lot like you, Bender.
Hey, thanks for noticing.
Just for that,
I'm gonna slip you into the 57th verse.
You can be my best friend
who abandons me when I need you.
Now, that's a verse we can all enjoy.
Well, Rodriguez ran to his best friend
Said, "Help me or I'll surely be killed"
Fry laughed and he said,
"You deserted me once
"Now it's your turn to feel the chill"
Lord, Lord
You've accurately portrayed
the nature of my grievance.
Big Caboose went lookin' for Rodriguez
Straight to New New York town
He cried...
Bender, guess what.
I met a fabulous girl
and we're engaged to be hitched.
That's great, Caboose.
Come on in and set a spell.
Oh, no time.
I got someplace to be.
See you soon, honeybunch.
Okay, dumpling.
My man's gone, gone.
Oh, I'm so lonely and easy.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
This is definitely going in the song.
He cried,
"Rambler,you slept with my Jezebel"
Hey, what's your name, anyhow?
Jezebel.
Oh, good,
I won't have to change any words.
Yeah, you're right. It's getting late.
I'll get your coat.
Oh, hey, Big Caboose.
What are you doing here on Earth?
I'm here for to see Ramblin' Rodriguez.
Well, he's at the railroad camp.
I know, but some strange force
drew me to New New York town.
That rambler slept with my Jezebel
Now I'm comin' for to shoot him down
Lord, Lord
Comin' for to shoot him down
Guess I'll go back
to the railroad camp now.
That's weird,
he sounded a lot like Bender's folk song.
Not a lot like Bender's folk song,
exactly like et cetera, et cetera.
His song is coming true somehow.
Oh, my God,
reality is infringing Bender's copyright.
"I'm comin' for to shoot you down"
No, wait.
"I'm comin' for to run you down"
With a train. Get it?
It's over, Jezebel.
Grab your things and get out.
I didn't bring any things.
That's what I like best about you, baby.
Rambler, you slept with my Jezebel,
and I'm comin' for to run you down,
Lord, Lord.
I'm comin' for to run you down
Fry, help! Let me in.
Bender?
What are you doing? It's 3:00 a.m.
I don't care if it's three B. M.
Open up and hide me!
I don't think so, Bender.
You deserted me once,
and now it's your turn to
"feel the chill."
Ha!
Breaker, breaker.
Hola.
Professor, help.
The hero of my folk song
tried to run me down,
and Fry refused to save me.
- That doesn't sound like me.
- Fry?
But you just...
Eh, I'll figure it out later.
But first I'll kill you!
Bender, stop.
We've been trying to warn you all night.
You didn't answer
your cell phone telephone,
so the Professor tried his CB.
Uh, scratch that, Rubber Turkey.
We got a 20 on the tin man.
Toodle-oo.
But Fry betrayed me at our apartment!
Just like in your folk song.
Somehow everything you sang about
is happening in real life.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Are you saying that guy at the apartment
was some kind of exact copy of Fry?
'Cause that's crazy.
He's a unique and beautiful object.
The printer.
Oh, I must have left
the wireless connection
to your folk song directory open.
Everything you wrote in the song
got routed straight to the 3-D printer.
Big Caboose, duplicate Fry, even Cookie
the crusty, comically inept
geological surveyor,
they're all made of nano-plastic.
So, if Bender had sung about,
I don't know,
some crazy giant land octopus
attacking me,
it would have actually happened?
I can't even imagine
singing about such a thing.
Well...
Fry, run!
Aw, relax, Beeler's stupid machine
takes hours to print anything.
No, it doesn't.
I improved it
using fancy modern technology.
Bender, whatever you do,
don't think about any more octopuses.
Octopuses?
I believe the correct plural is octopi.
I'm sorry.
"Octopuses" is also acceptable.
Think about puppies, Bender,
cute, harmless, dead puppies.
Don't worry.
I'll disconnect him from the printer.
No, wait, I know how to save Bender
from Big Caboose.
All he has to do
is write his way out of this mess,
and the 3-D printer will make it happen.
- Like how?
- Well, I don't know.
Make up another giant octopus
and have it kill Big Caboose.
What kind of lazy ending is that?
I'm not gonna put that in my song.
Hey, I have a cool idea.
Create a duplicate Bender,
so when Big Caboose kills it,
it's not real, it's duplicate.
Ooh, ooh, they did that on Star Trek: TNG.
Cram it, nerd.
I'm not going to just copy
some feel-good TV show wrap-up.
I can think of a hundred endings
that'll save you.
Just pick one.
No, Dr. Beeler, I won't just pick one.
My audience deserves better
than some crappy, formulaic ending.
If I must die, let me die
in a blaze of artistic integrity.
WELL...
Then the steel-drivin' man
Rammed his train through the wall
And crushed him flatter than a MacBook Air
Lord, Lord
Crushed him flatter than a MacBook Air
But while you were all out fighting
With the giant plastic octopi
I copied myself, you see...
Bender!
And I cowered in the bathroom
While that steel-drivin' moron
-Killed a duplicate instead of me
-Lord, lord
Killed a duplicate instead of me
Now, that's what I call a great ending.
I made a copy of myself
and Big Caboose killed him.
But you said making a copy of yourself
would be a lousy ending.
No, duplicate me said that.
See, I had to be sure he wouldn't try
and weasel out of getting killed
like I would and did,
so I created him with a tragic weakness:
artistic integrity.
Of course!
How could we have thought a guy
with integrity was you even for a second?
Because you're idiots.
Come on, Silicon Red, let's sell out.
I'm the real Rodriguez,
will you please stand up?
He been workin' on the railroad
Ladies can't get enough
I made a 3-D version of my worst nightmare
Sucker tried to stop the printer
and I found him there
Went 187 on his robot ass
Turned out to be a copy of my robot ass
Now we're folk-singin' players
packin' Beaujolais
And makin' max contributions to our 401K
Peace out.